

BACKEND · LEAD ENGINEER

□ (+84) 09-0632-3761 | ► hohuuphat22@gmail.com | ♣ https://phatho-dev.com/ | ☑ DeKal | ☐ phat-ho

Summary _

Technical Lead at NAB, working on developing the brand-new centralized and integrated platform supporting NAB internal bankers with their daily Credit Activities workload. 5+ years of algorithm background since high school. 7+ years of experience specializing in Backend development, infrastructure automation, and microservices. Super interest in solution design and performance optimization to meet customer needs.

Skills

DevOps AWS, Docker, ECS, Terraform, Jenkins **Code Quality** Jenkins, Checkmarkx, SonarQ, Sonatype

Back-end Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, REST API, Swagger, Redis, Kafka, Postgres

Front-end React, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQL

Languages English, Vietnamese

Work Experience _____

National Australia Bank

Ho Chi Minh City

Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Postgres, Kafka, Redis, AWS Lambda, AWS Glue.

LEAD BACKEND ENGINEER

11/2022 - now

- Onboard 2 new business areas into the system, currently supporting hundreds of bankers managing around 150k+ corporate and wholesale clients
- Continue to release big features for User Access Management and Client Management.
- Helping with release MVP for Credit Activity system and leading the backend integration between 3 squads.
- · Leading a squad to take over and own one of the most complicated pieces of Aurora, which is User Access Management.
- Successfully moved all devs work into Vietnam teams and expanded our team to 5 squads (nearly 50 people). This is the proof of our good delivery and quality, and it's everyone's contribution, not just individual.
- · Helping Solution Designer with all technical implementation (for my squad) so that he can focus on the high-level design.
- Establish regular meetings with backend members to address current issues, remove impediments, and give suggestions for continuous improvements.
- Helping devops with release checklist for all releases.
- Consulting Solution Designer for other better approaches for designing the system.
- Leading refactor legacy code from old developers for us to own the legacy system.
- Onboarding over hundreds of users into our Aurora system.
- Leading with fixing performance issues for our squad-level services.
- · Implementing a Redis cache layer, which reduces the over 8s of response into under 100ms for top-level executives.

SENIOR BACKEND ENGINEER 10/2021 – 11/2022

- After major release for MVPs, continue to work as a primary backend engineer of the whole team to build up a Document and Covenant Management System as well as an Alert Dashboard.
- Contribute to the born of our first squad BanhMi in Viet Nam (around 10-15 ppls) -> This means we will work independently with squads in Australia and India.
- Involving in training young engineers as well as hiring more people to work in the squad.
- Moving legacy data (covenants) into our new Aurora system.
- Introduce new document management system, uplift the bankers from working with their drive into one central place so that everything can be shared within the user access
- Devise a solution to solve the performance problems with listing covenants due to a series of complex business logic inside the DB queries. From the initial 30s performance time into 3s for top-level executives who have access to all data.
- Take over most of the backend work from other squads not from Vietnam -> work is moving gradually into Vietnam team because of our nest quality and good delivery

[&]quot;This is your life and it's ending one minute at a time."

Backend Engineer 5/2021 - 10/2021

• Joining a brand-new team with the initial of 3 people from Vietnam, working as a Backend engineer and co-operating closely with Australian engineers from Melbourne and Sydney as a squad of 10+ people.

- Release successfully the first version of the integrated platform (User Access Management, Banker Portfolio Dashboard, Facility Dashboard) to help bankers from nab working efficiently.
- · Help to train new engineers from India and Australia and walk them through the system design.
- · Advice Devops team to establish a flyway pipeline to help with migrations of the database efficiently
- · Advice with incidents and release issues of the whole backend system
- Help to build Vietnam team from 3 people to around 6-7 people

ZALORA Group

Ho Chi Minh City

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

10/2019 - 5/2021

- · Owning, maintaining and developing features for Zalora website on mobile devices in 6 countries.
- Working with state-of-the-art search engine in order to ensure that every search query in Zalora delivering meaningful and helpful results for customers.

LITE (WEB MOBILE)

Tech Stack: React CRA, Redux, Travis, DangerJS, BundleSize, Terraform, AWS Codebuild, AWS Lambda, AWS S3, Spinnaker, Scrutinizer, Lighthouse

- Released Earth Edit and Luxury and they are contributed to 15 % of total ZALORA Q3 2020
- Optimized service worker so that it worked for 6 countries and for 3 environments (instance/staging/production) without conflicting
- Moved building process from Jenkins to AWS Codebuild
- Rewrited Proxy to enable easy development from any environments
- Optimized/Filtered noise in error logs in Sentry
- Optimized bundle size under 150KB for main and 32KB for other chunks
- Added/Fixed proper eslint rule for the whole project
- Built deploying pipeline for releasing to staging/production with Jenkins
- · Built bot instance with AWS Lambda to help QA/Dev to deploy ticket easily to instance environment

Costa

Tech Stack: Golang, Docker, Solr, AWS ECS, Newrelic, Sentry, Grafana, AWS Cloudwatch

- Supported A/B testing for Learning to Ranks with Solr, third party Datajet, and many other features
- Reduced error rate on Newrelic to less than 1%
- Helped to improve caching with in-memory
- Moved Costa architecture from in-place deployment EC2 to ECS blue-green deployment
- Supported to refine errors and logging in Newrelic and Sentry

DEK Technology Ho Chi Minh city

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER & SCRUM GUARDIAN

04/2018 - 10/2019

Tech Stack: Ymer, Nodejs, Docker, Kafka Confluence, EFK, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Cassandra

- · Helped Scrum master to facilitate team, and came up with a solution to improve team performance
- Maintained and developed feature for Davis, a visualization tool helping people to have a statistic view of test cases executed by Jenkins.
- Launched and built Kafka connectors to actively pull the result from Jenkins using XPATH selectors and send the records to a Kafka cluster by interval.
- Researched optimizing backend data query time using hadoop HDFS + Apache Hive and compared with Cassandra.
- Deployed Kafka Confluence and Davis application (frontend + backend) to the provided Kubernetes cloud service.
- Developed a Logging system from a local machine using EFK stack (Elasticsearch, FluentD, Kibana), deployed also in Kubernetes
- Set up CI system using Jenkins and Gerrit and improve coverage of the source connector project to nearly 100% by refactoring project structure and adding Unit tests

Global Cybersoft Ho Chi Minh city

SOFTWARE ENGINEER FRESHER

07/2017 - 04/2018

Tech Stack: Java, Java Swing

- Maintained and developed new features for the desktop application project helping to operate industrial printing machines using Java Swing.
- · Drew a design diagram, writing test cases, fixed bugs on development tracks, and customer's requests.
- Worked closely with SE,QA,PM to resolve issues raised by customers asap.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN 06/2016 – 12/2016

Tech Stack: Spring MVC, Java, Hibernate framework, PostgreSQL, HTML/CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, Thymeleaf Bootstrap Framework

- Developed the surveillance system using Spring MVC framework in combination with Hibernate and PostgreSQL. The system will display recorded images from the camera after running them through the CV algorithm
- Worked as the core member of the team and helped to build the project structure from the beginning.
- Presented the demo of the project to stakeholders and clients by the end of each sprint.

March 16, 2024 Ho Phat · Résumé 2



DeKal PortfolioHo Chi Minh

FRONTEND 11/2019 – now

- Built my portfolio project from scratch using the cutting-edge framework Nextjs.
 Tech Stack: Nextjs, DangerJS, CircleCI, Vercel, Lighthouse, Scrutinizer
- Configured app deployment with Vercel.
- Configured CI/CD pipeline with Github, DangerJS, Vercel, CircleCI, and Scrutinizer
- · Configured performance CI tool with LightHouse. The performance test will run on opening/updating a pull request.
- Adding simple release mechanism and CHANGLOG.md to track the versions.
- Visit my page at here.

BACKEND + CMS

- Built an api backend using Spring MVC Framework allows frontend to fetch neccessary configs and blogs from MongoDB.
 Tech Stack: Spring MVC, Java, DangerJS, CircleCI, Heroku, Swagger, Codecov, Gradle, React CRA, Redux, MongoDB
- Integrated a CMS frontend to allow users to easily do modifications/add/update data.
- Built mechanism to include CMS frontend bundle from Reactjs into static resources to serve with Spring MVC.
- Deployed using Heroku pipeline Review Staging Production.
- Configured CI/CD pipeline with Github, DangerJS, CircleCI, Heroku, and Codecov.
- Built a release script with net.researchgate.release and Git Changelog Gradle.
- · Setup Swagger to document apis.

Boot Career United State

Tech Lead & Scrum Master 08/2020 – now

- · Re-architect the old application with ReactJS and refactor it to better project structure with Redux ToolKit.
- · Defined team rituals, team working process on tech side and way of workings following Agile Scrum.
- · Splitting tasks by features and coordinating members to work on it.
- Helped to refine the working process and removed impediments.

JOBSEEKER DASHBOARD

- A web application for helping people from non-traditional backgrounds and underrepresented communities get jobs in tech
 Tech Stack: React CRA, Redux Toolkit, Storybook, eslint, lerna, React Testing library, CircleCI, Netlify
- Re-architect the old application with ReactJS and refactor it to better project structure with Redux ToolKit.
- Broke down the design part by part and coordinated team members to do the task.
- Setup CI/CD with Circle CI, Eslist, and Netlify.
- Setup a storybook, to isolate components for independently development.
- Built a proper project structure based module and good global state management flow.
- Built a release pipeline with CHANGLOG and github tags.

USER SERVICE

- A Nodejs Application to store data of candidate and user signing up to the system.
 - Tech Stack: Typescript, Nodejs, Express, Toolkit, Eslint, Terraform, Github action, Heroku, MongoDB
- Re-architect and convert the whole application built with Nodejs Express Framework from Javascript to Typescript.
- · Integrated Swagger with the backend service.
- Setup CI/CD with Github action, Eslist, and Heroku pipeline.
- Built a new project using terraform to manage the infrastructure of the whole organization (Infrastructure as Code).

Popswap Sweden

FREELANCER 06/2020 - 09/2020

- Maintained the application allowing people to swipe for swapping clothes and items like Tinder.
- Tech Stack: React Native, Redux, Android, IOS
- Restructure the structure of the React Native application, adds new scripts to deploy, remove tricky hack of the old owner and create a smooth environment for development.
- Removed old/stale features that existed in the application.

Refactored/redesigned the application with new looks.

· Added integration with swish bank and developed new premium features with Google and Apple store.

Максн 16, 2024 Но Рнат · Résumé 3

Live GuessHo Chi Minh city

TEAM LEAD 3/2019 – 5/2019

- Built a system to allow users guessing based on events using ReactJS.
 Tech Stack: ReactJS, Webpack, Redux, Docker, Apache Cordorva
- Use long-polling to sync events continuously with the current time.
- Create the UI with interactive timer and lively interaction.
- Used Cordorva to build an application version based on the web mobile app for android
- Built docker container to deploy directly on Client server

Honors & Awards

VIETNAM

2015	12th Place, ACM-ICPC VietNam Southern Provincial Programming Contest	Ho Chi Minh city
2013	2rd Place , Olympic cấp trường Khoa học tự nhiên	Ho Chi Minh city
2012	3rd Place , Học sinh giỏi cấp thành phố	Ho Chi Minh city
2011	1rd Place , Học sinh giỏi cấp thành phố	Ho Chi Minh city
2011	3rd Place , Tin học trẻ	Ho Chi Minh city

Research work.

Analyzing and Detecting Sentiment of Readers through their Comments on News Articles in Vietnamese

GRADUATE THESIS 3/2017-9/2017

Key words: Sentiment Analysis, Crawler, Online Press, Comments

Our thesis targeted the data from VNExpress's comment for sentiment classification. The data was collected from comments into the database automatically at the specific time of the day by the crawler built in the server. After the crawling process, with SVM, we labeled data into sentiment values (positive, negative and neutral). Finally, we build a web system using Java in order to extract the evaluated data.

Education

Vietnam University of Science Ho Chi Minh city

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2013 - 2017

• Degree Classification: Very Good

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Ho Chi Minh city

AWS CERTIFICATEView Cert.

AWS Certified Cloud Pratitioner Ho Chi Minh city

AWS CERTIFICATE

2022

2024

• View Cert.

English Certificate Ho Chi Minh city

TOEFL IBT 2015

• 85 pts